Mr. vampire
executive producer : Leonard ho koon-cheung
producer : Sammo hung kam-Bo
planning : Eric tsang chi-wai , Barry wong ping-yiu
executive planner : Jacob cheung chi-leung
production manager : Jessica chan pui-wah
director : Ricky lau koon-wai
Dear uncles , brothers , and sisters , please come back for dinner .
Anyone passing our door is also a guest . You guys first .
Dear friends , you 're welcome .
Don 't go out . When you go out , they 're full of life .
Lucky .
If all you brothers start to wreak havoc , I wouldn 't know how to catch you .
Time to eat .
One , two , three , four , five , six , seven , eight .
Eight , seven , six , five , four , three , two , one .
The number 's right .
Game over !
Don 't be afraid , it 's me .
You bastard !
Look at you .
Jeez ! No need to hide ! I told you it was me !
Master , help !
- What 's wrong ? - Master , inside ...
Master , it 's me !
Whoa ! Why 're you so heavy-handed , senior ?
Broken bones !
You don 't need to , I 'll do it .
I 'll do it .
They can 't feel anything !
Dentures ?
Senior , how can it be ?
They 're all broken .
How can I explain ?
Come and help , then !
You two guys !
Play all you want , but don 't play with my brothers !
- Uncle , he ... - Say no more ! I 'm leaving .
Stay two more days .
Senior , this ...
Hope to see you again .
" Vast is the sky
" boundless are the wilds "
going home , lined up in a row .
Step-by-step , out of the mortuary .
Let 's hit the road !
It 's really late , why 're you still here ?
In a minute your aunt will ask me about you , go home !
Uncle , I 'll help you .
- Good morning . - Uncle gau , good morning .
- So early ? - Business good ?
- Good morning . - Whoa ! Why 're you all dressed up ?
- What 's up ? - Master 's taking me to western tea .
Hurry along !
Master , can I not go with you to meet master yam ?
What 's wrong ?
Have you had any arguments with master yam ?
Nol
I don 't even know what he looks like .
It 's just , I 'm all grown up , and haven 't tasted western tea .
I 'm afraid I 'll make a fool of myself and embarrass master , that 's all .
Rarely do you think of your master 's reputation .
Good , very good !
You 're afraid of embarrassing master ?
Well , you best not go then .
I 've never had western tea .
If I make a fool of myself , it 'll be very disgraceful .
No , I 'll take man choi with me .
If anyone has to be disgraced , I 'll let him do it first .
Man choi !
I 'm over here !
Master , you called me ?
Now , seeing as you 're so well-behaved today ,
I 'm taking you in to enlighten you on how to have western tea .
Great ...
Let 's go .
Sir , do you have a reservation ?
I don 't .
Didn 't yam fat make a reservation for us ?
Master yam ? Please follow me .
Please .
This way .
- Uncle gau . - Master yam .
How are you ? Please sit .
- Greet master yam . - Master yam .
That 's alright , have a seat .
Please sit .
I hear your daughter has returned from the capital .
Didn 't you come together ?
That girl ? She finished studying cosmetology .
She 's been teaching people everywhere since she got back .
Jeez , seeing how ugly you look , your daughter can 't be pretty !
Speak of the devil ...
- Dad . - Greet uncle gau .
Uncle gau .
Sit .
She 's all grown up .
Yeah , very grown up !
What would you like to drink ?
- I want coffee . - Ok .
Caw-fee ?
- Give me a cup of coffee . - I want coffee , too !
Master , are you having anything ?
- I 'll have a coffee , too . - Ok .
Master , I don 't want coffee , I want ... coffee , ok ?
The order 's been taken , leave it .
Uncle gau , regarding the reburial of my late father 's coffin .
I wonder if you 've chosen an auspicious day already ?
I feel that you should think it over first .
In this type of situation , it would be better not to move him .
I 've thought it over thoroughly .
Back then , the feng shui master , said :
' Twenty years from now , the coffin must be reburied ' .
This will be good for us .
You shouldn 't believe what a feng shui master says !
Then I shouldn 't believe what you say !
That 's right !
Children shouldn 't interrupt adults when they 're talking .
In that case , let 's prepare to rebury in three days ' time , between 3 and 5 pm .
What are we going to prepare ?
Money , of course !
How much do you want ?
Small tokens ...
Master yam , ' millionaire ' wong is here .
He 's over there .
I 'm going over to say ' hello ' .
Uncle gau , as you please .
- Look after them , serve some custard tarts . - Sure .
Master , which of the two cups do I drink first : Black or white ?
Are you that thirsty ?
Uncle gau , my apologies .
Coffee needs to be drunk whilst hot .
Help yourself .
Please .
Uncle gau , you like drinking plain coffee ?
Yes , I like drinking plain coffee .
Dad , I 'll add milk for you .
Good .
Come ...
Dad , I want to buy some Rouge gouache .
Go ahead , I 'll find you in a little while .
- Eat . - Sure !
My pleasure .
Have you no manners ?
Master yam , how many spoonfuls of sugar would you like ?
No need ...
You like to eat a plain tart ?
Then I 'll do it myself .
Master , it 's very sweet !
Imagine you 're eating candy .
I 'm going to buy groceries now .
Soon , a hooker from happy red court will come in to do her shopping .
You better not bully her just because she 's a prostitute .
Got it , auntie ! You go get your groceries first .
Always charge hookers 30 % extra .
I know what to do .
Excuse me , may I ask where can I buy Rouge gouache ?
Wow ! So pretty !
I wish she could be my wife .
What a pity !
Miss , please look around .
My aunt told me you were coming .
Who 's your aunt ?
The lady you were talking to just now .
I just asked her where I could buy Rouge gouache ?
I don 't know her at all .
Pretending ?
Never mind if you don 't know my aunt .
Try this kind of Rouge .
It 's pretty good .
So , when did you learn to ... ?
Learn to do this ?
Learning is the same as doing .
When I was twelve , my mum taught me .
What ? Your mum taught you ?
Yes !
Unfortunately , she died prematurely .
So , I had to go to the capital to learn .
This colour 's so beautiful .
How old are you now ?
Eighteen years old .
So , she 's been doing it for six years ?
Have you ever thought about when you 'll stop working ?
No .
If I 'm not dead at eighty , I 'll carry on doing it .
You 're not being forced ?
My goodness ! This is my hobby , why would I be forced ?
All women like doing this .
Have you ever thought about leaving ?
No .
I want to take what I 've learnt in the capital ,
and teach it to the girls here .
They 're going to love it .
It 's a good job you 're happy , but you mustn 't corrupt others , too !
How can you be so backward thinking ?
It 's not backward thinking , it 's a question of morality .
Let 's call it a day . I won 't do business with you .
Please go back across the street to your happy red court .
Hey , what 's going on at happy red court ?
So , here you are !
Why 're you so angry ?
You 've been to happy red court ?
- No . - How do you know her , then ?
She 's master yam 's daughter , miss ting-ting .
What kind of place is happy red court ?
- Teahouse . - Brothel .
What ?
- Restaurant . - Brothel .
What did you say ?
Brothel !
You think I 'm ... ?
Miss !
- If something goes wrong ... - Dad !
I 'm g 0 ing n 0 w
my good girl !
- Master yam . - Ting-ting ...
What the hell 's going on ?
Naughty boy !
Now , you must all pay your Sincere respects .
Uncle gau .
Back then , the feng shui master said , of this hard-to-find grave ,
it 's a good plot .
Correct .
This grave is called " dragonfly touches the water lightly . "
The grave should be thirty feet in length and have the four realities .
The width should be ten feet and have three realities .
Therefore , the coffin may not be buried horizontally .
It must be buried under Buddhist law .
Very impressive , uncle Gaul !
French burial ? Master , what 's a French burial ?
Is that a funeral for the French ?
French , your ass !
Uncle gau , finished praying ? Can we start digging ?
You can .
Start work .
Master , what exactly is a Buddhist law burial ?
What we call a Buddhist law burial is a vertical burial .
Am I right ?
Right !
The feng shui master said ...
" If an ancestor is buried vertically , the next generation will be fine . "
Has it been good ?
These past twenty years or so , our family business has gotten worse and worse .
I don 't know why .
Could it be the feng shui master has a grudge against your family ?
A grudge ?
Did your father have enmity with him whilst he was alive ?
This piece of land was originally his .
Father knew it was a good grave ,
so he bought it for a huge sum of money .
Merely by enticement ? Was there coercion ?
99 % probability .
Otherwise , why would he have played such a big trick on you ?
As payback , he had this dragonfly grave covered with cement .
So what should we do ?
" Dragonfly touches the water lightly . " It should be covered with snowflakes .
If the coffin lid can 't lightly touch water , how can the dragonfly ?
At least he had the conscience to tell you to rebury after twenty years .
Thus , harming only half your life and not your whole life .
Then harming your generation and not the next eighteen !
I see it !
Loosen the lid , pull out the nails .
Everyone , today grandpa yam will see the light again .
All those aged : Thirty-six , twenty-two ,
thirty-five and forty-eight ,
born the year of the rooster or ox , turn around now to avoid .
Everyone , straighten your clothes .
Open the coffin .
Dad !
Grandpa !
Please forgive your unfilial son for disturbing your eternal sleep .
Uncle gau , can 't we reuse this plot ?
" Dragonfly touches the water lightly " ,
but never touches the same location twice .
This grave is already wasted .
What should we do ?
I propose on-the-spot cremation .
Cremation ? No way !
My late father was most afraid of fire .
I couldn 't do that to him .
Master yam , this is most unusual .
Whatever you do is fine , as long as it 's not cremation .
Can 't you think of any other way ?
Alright . He can stay in our mortuary for the time being .
I 'll help find another plot for your father tomorrow .
So that he may rest in peace .
Alright . Close the coffin lid and carry it back to the mortuary .
Master yam , please go back first .
You two , burn some plum blossom incense over the plot .
When the burning 's done , come back and let me know .
Burn incense over all the other graves , too .
Dead at the age of twenty ?
What a waste !
This one 's for you .
It won 't be wasted .
Thank you .
Look , it 's burnt like this !
Go , let 's tell master !
People fear " three long and two short " the most .
The most fearsome joss sticks are " two short and one long " .
It 's unfortunate they burnt like this .
The family that produces these sticks , will surely have someone die .
You mean master yam 's family ?
You don 't say ?
Nothing to do with me , not my problem .
Won 't master yam 's daughter be affected ?
Basically , anyone with the yam name will be in trouble .
Then , ting-ting ...
Didn 't you say , " nothing to do with me , not my problem " ?
How could that be the same ?
If I save my sweetheart 's life , marrying her won 't be a problem .
- Hey ! - Hey !
- Fair competition ? - Fine !
That 's right , master .
I 've thought about it already .
Why else would I ask you to carry the coffin back ?
What 's wrong with the coffin ?
There 's nothing wrong with the coffin .
It 's the corpse that 's the problem .
I also think something 's not right .
Yeah , it hasn 't rotted in twenty years !
Whoa ! It 's put on weight , too !
Quick , cover the lid !
Prepare paper , brush , ink , knife , and sword .
- What ? - What ?
Yellow paper , red brush , black ink , real knife , and wooden sword !
Master , using a chicken again ?
Chicken ...
Hold this , windbag .
Hey , what 's that ?
An ink line marker .
Master , where do we pluck ?
Pluck the ink lines over the coffin .
Pluck over the entire coffin .
People are divided into good and bad .
The dead are divided into corpses and vampires .
Not just good and bad people , but also male and female .
I 'm talking about all people , not just the bad ones !
Old master yam is a corpse that 's on the verge of becoming a vampire .
How can a corpse turn into a vampire ?
Yeah , and how can people turn bad ?
People turn bad because they fail to live up to expectations .
Corpses turn into vampires because they have one last breath .
" One last breath " ? What do you mean ?
When a person dies with grievances , or stress , they suffocate to death .
They 'll have a single breath accumulated in the throat .
That means he 's dead , but hasn 't stopped breathing ?
That 's why it 's important to put on your best behaviour .
It 's vital when a person dies they breathe their last .
If the dead don 't stop breathing , then they will harm others .
Keep plucking and stop the chatter .
Let me know when you 're done , and you mustn 't overlook a pluck .
Ok , it 's done .
Make sure you haven 't missed a pluck .
- I have . - Where ?
Herel
you bastard !
- Here ! - Don 't you run !
Stop playing ...
Master .
Tricking me ?
Bastard , hold this !
You ...
You don 't care about me ?
You got me into trouble .
Who asked you to pluck the ink line marker at me ?
Hey , going home this late ? You 're liable to bump into ghosts .
Good lord !
The situation we 're in now ,
I 'd rather bump into a ghost than see master !
" Her gaze ...
â   Like ... stars shining in the sky .
" Seeing you ... my heart skips a beat .
" Her gaze ...
â   Like ... stars shining in the sky .
" Seeing you ... my heart skips a beat .
" The moon rises brightly , an ill wind blows through Willow alley .
" It 's the female ghost searching for a lover .
" Who wants to love the mournful ghost bride ?
" Accompany the female ghost
" on a dark night to secretly worship the moon .
" Her gaze ...
â   Like ... stars shining in the sky .
" Seeing you ... my heart skips a beat .
" Her gaze ...
â   Like ... stars shining in the sky .
" Seeing you ... my heart skips a beat .
" Unwilling to look at the bright moon ... "
Sleeps like a dead pig .
You 're the perfect type of person to guard a mortuary .
Drink tea .
Ah wai , nothing to do today at the yamen ?
Oh , trivial matters I just hand over to my subordinates .
Cousin ting-ting 's all grown-up now .
Ting-ting ? She 's not a child anymore .
Then she should get married , eh ?
She should ...
So , I think ...
No tea ? I 'll pour for you .
Master , uncle gau 's here .
- Please . - Master yam .
Uncle gau , how 's the coffin reburial going ?
It 's finally coming along .
Let 's talk in my study then .
Fine .
You two better not mess around .
Uncle-in-law , I still think ...
We 'll talk in a minute .
Miss yam , I 'm sorry about last time . I misunderstood you .
- Forget it . - Hey !
You two hanging around ? Want to steal something ?
Standing beside my cousin ! You want to take advantage ?
Cousin .
Now , my cousin wants to scold you , but doesn 't want to make a fuss .
Right , cousin ?
Right , we were wrong .
We shouldn 't be in here .
Let 's go into the garden .
White hair ! A sign of premature ageing .
- Is it yours ? - No ! How can it be mine ?
How could you have found this white hair on me ?
Cousin , what I said to uncle-in-law just now ... you should understand .
We 've been friends since childhood .
Even though you played in your home and I played in mine .
This can be considered playing since childhood .
But , we 've been together for so long , yet I haven 't even touched your hand .
Not like those two boors outside .
Hey , you swallow it .
Me ?
Of course ! You pulled out the hair .
Now , once you swallow it , you 'll be at one with him .
Then we can bully him , ok ?
Got it ? Oki
try slapping yourself .
Hey , if he hits himself , then what ?
Jeez ! No way are people in this world stupid enough to beat themselves !
Hit harder !
You mustn 't stop !
What are you doing ?
Hey , why did you stop ?
It really hurts !
I 'll help you hit !
Let go ! Cousin !
Cousin !
I 'm a boor , I deserve a beating !
There really are people in this world stupid enough to beat themselves !
I 'm not playing ...
Not playing ?
Now we 're playing him .
How can we let him play us ?
We 'll turn it back on him !
- Undress . - How can I ?
What 's there to fear ? He 's inside , and you 're out here .
Let ting-ting see him get naked .
Right .
Cousin !
Dad !
Naughty boy !
Playing tricks again ?
Go back !
Uncle-in-law , I just want to drink tea ...
There 's been a murder at the yam residence !
You can 't come in here !
Master yam died a cruel death .
Cousin , even though uncle-in-law is dead ,
you can always count on me .
Hey , don 't recklessly touch him !
Right .
Hey , you two , hurry back to the mortuary ,
see if old master yam 's corpse is still there .
Brother wai , what weapon was used to kill master yam ?
He must have been shot dead .
Every shot hit his neck ?
He must be a martial arts master .
Throwing darts are very accurate .
Throwing a ... A nine-chain money dart .
That 's what killed master yam .
Where are the darts ?
Hey ! Don 't obstruct my deductions , ok ?
You 're so smart , you explain how he died .
Go on !
My theory is that he was stabbed to death by fingernails .
Stabbed to death by fingernails ?
That means only very long fingernails could have done it , right ?
Dear village elders , does anyone have longer fingernails than him ?
Don 't talk nonsense !
I wouldn 't wrongly accuse someone .
Your fingernails are the longest in the entire village .
So , you appear to be the prime suspect .
- Men , come here ! - Yes !
- Lock him up ! - Yes !
Cousin , the suspect has been caught .
Cousin will avenge his uncle-in-law .
Cousin , you must investigate thoroughly .
You mustn 't frame someone .
Got it ...
Come ! Carry master yam 's corpse back to the yamen .
Yes !
I 'll make you face him all day .
You 'll confess for sure !
- Take him away ! - Yes !
- Master , the coffin ... - Split open !
- The corpse ... - Gone !
- Master , you 're ... ? - Master , you 're ... ?
Busted !
You ...
Don 't mess around .
Captain , may I have a few words with them ?
Say your last words .
Don 't say I 'm unsympathetic .
Have you checked it out thoroughly ?
I even checked the other coffins ... Nothing .
Something seriously bad will happen tonight .
I know .
Master , you 'll be in jail .
Jail 's a small matter .
At any moment , two vampires will arise .
Two ?
Master yam was killed by a vampire .
Its poison entered his heart .
So , he 'll become a vampire , too .
Father and son ? Talk about a double threat !
Hey , you done talking ?
Almost done .
Chau sang , smuggle all my work tools into the yamen tonight .
Man choi , you stay here to protect ting-ting .
How do I protect her ?
If you meet a vampire , don 't breathe .
Then you 'll be alright .
Don 't breathe ?
Master , what should I bring tonight ?
Chicken blood , ink line marker , string , paper talismans ... bring them all .
Hey ... that 's enough ...
Anything left to say , save it for your funeral .
Move !
Hey ! Glutinous rice !
Remember to bring glutinous rice .
You can 't come in , move away !
Tonight , I 'll avenge my uncle-in-law .
Talk ! Why did you kill my uncle-in-law ?
Why would I want to kill your uncle-in-law ?
So stubborn !
Do you know what this character is ?
Hey ... don 't be reckless !
Why can 't I be reckless ?
I use this character ' bad ' to brand bad guys like you .
When the brand is put on the chest , it sticks to the flesh .
Now , I use this character . The strokes are small and clear .
But , it 's just as painful .
- Come on . - Yes !
- Hold this . - Yes .
This character is ' wicked ' .
If you don 't want the character ' wicked ' branded on your chest ,
just like this pigskin ,
then you 'll have to confess before dawn .
- If ... - If you don 't release me before dawn ,
you 'll be responsible for the consequences .
You dare answer back ? How can this be ?
- Take him down . - Yes !
Uncle-in-law , I 'll take revenge for you .
May you rest in peace .
Make a confession by tomorrow .
What are you standing there for ?
Nothing .
I 'm just waiting for you to pull your head back in .
Why ?
I 'm afraid you 'll be embarrassed .
Embarrassed , my ass !
Quick , help me get my head back in .
Don 't push ...
Can you please just use your brain ?
Sure !
Master , no matter what I do , don 't blame me .
Fine . Hurry up !
What are you doing ? Why did you pull down my trousers ?
There , it 's back in now , isn 't it ?
- Damn kid ... - Hey , master !
We had an agreement .
You said , I wouldn 't be blamed for anything I did .
Did you bring everything ?
Yes .
Chicken blood , ink , talismans , ink line marker .
The glutinous rice ?
Yeah , it 's here .
It 's still hot , master .
- Eat while it 's hot . - You cooked it ?
I wanted raw glutinous rice .
I need it to sprinkle around , to block the vampire 's breath !
Then ... what do we do now ?
Should I try feeding him ?
It 's moving ! Master , he 's moving !
Here , stick this talisman on his forehead .
Master , he 's gone .
Go find him .
Go !
Hurry up !
What 's going on ... ? What 's happening ?
- Go check it out ! - Yes !
What 're you afraid of ? It 's my uncle-in-law .
- He 's on our side . - Yes !
- Quick , make up the bed . - Yes !
Uncle-in-law , fortunately your nephew here came just in time .
Otherwise , I don 't know how they 'd torment you .
Brother wai , it 's all done .
- Quickly , move him back into bed . - Yes .
You two , go out now and keep the door closed .
You 're not to open the door no matter what , understand ?
Yes !
Uncle-in-law ... watch this .
Don 't tear off the talisman !
Still hiding ?
Come out and be put behind bars .
Look out , behind you !
Behind me ? Behind me is my uncle-in-law .
- Uncle-in-law , he 's ... - He 's become a vampire !
Run !
Get down !
Open the door ...
We won 't , no matter what !
I 'm your beloved captain , brother wai .
Open the door ...
Open the door ! Hurry , open the door !
Open the door ... hurry up ...
Help me ...
Uncle gau , help !
Hurry , throw the keys over !
Catch !
Hurry up , help me !
Nobody breathe !
Stop chasing me !
Master , I 'll help you .
Whatever you do , don 't pull down my trousers , ok ?
Ok ! There are many ways .
Uncle gau , help !
Good job ! Open the gate !
Uncle gau , hurry up and save me ...
Pull the ink line marker .
Open the door ... Hurry , open the door ...
It 's nearly dawn .
I don 't think he 'll come .
You 've been waiting all night .
You should go back and sleep .
No way .
Who 's going to protect you when I 'm gone ?
But you don 't have to hold that bamboo pole .
Don 't look down on this bamboo .
I crafted it with great care .
It 's just that I 'm not using it now .
Wow , so pretty !
No need to be afraid , I 'll protect you .
Don 't breathe .
I can 't stand it !
Quickly , get something to tie up your grandpa .
Hurry ...
Ha ! Not only can I talk now , I can even sing !
" This trap ... meant for me ... "
Run !
Master ...
Man choi , help !
Man choi .
Jump down .
Chase ...
Why aren 't you chasing ?
What 're you afraid of ? Useless !
Lucky he can run quick , or I would 've shot him !
- Hey , are any of you injured ? - No ...
Master , man choi was injured .
Will he become a vampire ?
It 's possible .
Quick , move away ! Let me shoot him dead !
I said it was possible .
We can still save him .
- How do you save him ? - With what ?
With glutinous rice .
Glutinous rice can eliminate the corpse 's poison ,
and prevent vampirification .
Glutinous rice ?
Ting-ting , you mustn 't stay here .
Move into my house temporarily .
Great !
So comfortable .
You don 't need to worry , I 'll be alright when the poison is removed .
I was never worried .
Aren 't you scared I 'll become a vampire ?
Not scared , just afraid .
Does your wound hurt ?
No pain .
Of course , your flesh is hard as a rock .
How could it hurt ?
Master , are you trying to scare me ?
Scare you ?
There , you see ?
No reaction at all .
How could that be ?
Soon , the corpse 's poison will spread through your body .
Then , even if I chop you into pieces , you won 't feel a thing .
What should I do ?
Move .
Move what ?
Move your arms and legs . Basically , keep moving .
Don 't stop .
What happens if I stop ?
Stop , and your blood won 't circulate , it 'll congeal into clots .
What happens if it clots ?
If it clots , it hardens .
What happens if it hardens ?
Hard is stiff , stiff is hard .
What happens if it stiffens ?
Once it stiffens , you become a vampire .
After that , I wouldn 't know what to do .
So , what do I do now ?
What do you do ? Still sitting there ?
Quick , get up and move !
Go inside and sprinkle glutinous rice on the bed .
Ting-ting , please cook glutinous rice congee for man choi to eat .
No matter what , don 't let smoke get into the glutinous rice .
Otherwise , eating it will be useless .
Master , that 's all the glutinous rice we have left .
Go and buy some , cook it when you 're back .
Take off your shoes and jump on the bed .
I 've heard of moaning in bed , but what 's jumping on the bed ?
If the corpse 's poison gets in your feet it 'll spread very easily .
Master , what use is glutinous rice ?
Glutinous rice is used to detoxify corpses .
Master , it 's stabbing my feet .
If you don 't like it , sweep it aside .
I like it ...
Go buy glutinous rice , then come back .
Is long-grain rice ok ?
Sure , if you think he 's beyond saving , buy long-grain rice .
Good !
You bastard !
Get down ! You trying to hurt me ?
Get down ...
Jump !
Glutinous rice
hey ... stupid boy !
It 's pouring all over ...
Your help does more harm than good .
Pick it all up !
Telling him to pick it up ? You show me how .
Sweep it .
Quickly , get something to sweep it .
I 'm so clever .
How could I have such a stupid son ?
What ? You 're blaming me ?
No .
Your son hasn 't stopped all day .
That 's weird .
Why are the neighbouring villagers racing here to buy glutinous rice ?
I hear there are vampires over there .
Some people say glutinous rice can cure vampires .
I 've heard of glutinous rice treating woodlice .
Glutinous rice curing vampires ?
Can it really ?
I don 't care if it 's true or not .
If we have good business , then we 'll sell it !
I 'm afraid we don 't have enough glutinous rice to sell .
Why are you so stupid ?
If there isn 't enough , mix in long-grain rice .
Right ! No one will know .
Hey , we have business .
Boss .
Sir , what are you buying ?
Seriously ? You 're asking what I 'm buying in a rice shop ?
Oh , there 's plenty !
We have rice sacks , rice vats , rice hoists , rice cups .
We have containers for all rice .
Rice flour , rice crackers , rice cakes , rice biscuits .
We sell everything here people eat .
Also , rice husks , rice dregs , burnt rice .
We also sell to feed the pigs .
Any type of rice there is , we have it here .
As many as I have pimples .
So , you sell " rice fields ' here , too ?
Sure ! Now , as boss , mine sells for three cents a catty .
The assistant 's is just one cent a catty .
Because we eat differently , so too are our excretions different .
In fact , the quality 's about the same .
It 's best to use on vegetables .
How much do you want ?
Not for me , I 'm busy right now .
Can you please hurry and get me fifty catties of glutinous rice .
Sure ! Bring a rice sack .
Come ... let me .
Oh , yeah ! Boss ...
It must be pure . Don 't mix it .
Sure ...
Ah sau , come here ...
Must be pure , got it ? Fifty catties .
Mix in thirty catties of long-grain rice .
- Do it . - Boss !
Coming ... do it !
Hey , what have you got that can curb my hunger for now ?
Curb hunger ? Then ... that 's not right .
Come on . Rice cracker ?
They 're great !
- Not bad . - Great , huh ?
Try a fried rice cake .
You haven 't tried the fried rice cakes .
Aromatic ?
Tasty ?
Oh , yeah . How much , boss ?
Five bucks .
- There . - Thanks !
Dad , it 's ready .
Whoa , it 's so heavy !
We don 't rig the scales .
Don 't you worry .
Hey , that 's a heavy sack .
Rascal , did you mix in long-grain rice ?
Yeah , thirty catties .
How much glutinous rice ?
You said fifty catties .
Eighty catties ?
No , dad .
I only gave him forty-five catties of glutinous rice .
Now , forty-five catties of glutinous rice ...
Thirty catties of long-grain rice ...
Dad , your count is wrong . Correct should be seventy-five catties .
Count my ass !
First watch of the night .
Uncle .
Young lady , you almost scared me to death !
Are you alright ?
Uncle , can you do me a favour ?
Help you with what favour ?
I 'm extremely busy .
It 's very simple .
Hurry up and molest me .
What ? Me molest you ?
Yes , hurry up . Molest me .
You 're a slut !
I won 't let you steal my integrity .
Don 't even dare !
No ...
Molestation ...
Whoa ! What kind of world is this ?
Hey !
You !
Miss ...
You 've really got guts ! In broad daylight ...
No , taking advantage of a respectable woman in public !
It 's her !
Still trying to explain ?
Miss , are you alright ?
I 'm really scared .
That 's very easy .
Where do you live ? I 'll take you home .
My home is right here .
Wait for me a minute , I 'll go back and get my things .
Anyone in the house ? Come out and help .
One of your members is hurt .
My family lives in the provincial capital .
There 's no one else in this house except you and me .
Is this god 's will ?
What did you say ?
Nothing ...
Be careful .
Sit .
I really don 't know how to thank you .
Well ... think about it yourself .
The means of gratitude between men and women ,
is usually one and the same .
How 's that ?
Here , let me make a hypothesis .
If I hadn 't been passing this place ,
I may not have rescued you in time .
This kind of coincidence is known as fate .
Also , if I weren 't a righteous man ,
I wouldn 't have disregarded my own safety to rescue you .
This kind of behaviour is known as righteousness .
Then , if I hadn 't felt protective of you ,
I wouldn 't have bothered bringing you back .
Now , this kind of behaviour is known as affection .
There 's affection , righteousness , and , on top of that , fate .
Ask yourself , how you should repay me ?
I think I should give you my heart .
That 's what most people would do .
May I trouble you to wait a moment ?
That was too easy .
In these situations , typically , there are only two possibilities .
Either I 'm dreaming ... Or I just met a ghost .
Miss , I was talking casually just now .
It 's not my nature to take advantage of you .
I have to go do something tonight .
If it 's fate , I 'm sure I 'll meet you again tomorrow .
If I stay here , it would have to be god 's will .
Is it really god 's will ?
Whoa , how come it 's so chilly ?
If you leave in a rainstorm like this , you 're liable to catch cold .
If you must leave , why not have a cup of wine before you go ?
May as well . A cup of wine won 't kill me .
Drink the wine .
Thanks .
Rain 's stopped , time to go home ...
Man choi .
Man choi ! Wake up quickly !
If uncle gau found out you were sleeping ,
he would beat you again .
It can 't be !
I 'm done for .
I 'm turning today for sure !
Can 't let him see this , or he 'll kill me for sure .
I must persevere .
Even if I become a vampire ,
I want to live a long vampiric life .
How can this be ?
Brother wai !
- You 're here so early . - Oh , no .
The neighbourhood watch was concerned about man choi turning into a vampire .
So , I came to have a look .
Please have a look .
- Man choi ! - Coming !
See ... see for yourself if I 've become a vampire .
Hold this .
I 'm back !
Where were you last night ?
You 're only back now ?
No , I went to the neighbouring village .
What did you do last night ?
Nothing . I arrived at the village yesterday .
Suddenly there was lightning , Gale winds and heavy rain .
I feared the glutinous rice would get wet ,
so hid in a house to shelter from the rain .
Hey , I was patrolling the streets last night .
There wasn 't any rain .
I can back him up . It didn 't rain a single drop last night .
Brother , you 're only back now ? Want me to starve to death ?
Don 't stop !
Who were you hiding in the house with ?
Uncle gau , what 's going on now ?
Don 't say man choi 's now beyond saving ?
No , what 's wrong that you had to come see me ?
Oh , nothing ! I want us to go catch the vampire together .
The vampire 's already been stung by the line marker .
Its hands and feet can 't move .
Now 's the time to catch it .
Where 's a good place to catch him ?
Somewhere dark and wet .
- Let 's go now , then ! - I can 't , I have to watch over them .
Them ?
No ! You must go now .
When it gets dark , he 'll be fiercer than you .
Hey , are you afraid ?
- Afraid of what ? Let 's go ! - Yes !
- Let 's go ! - Yes !
Brother wai , there 's hardly anyone here to begin with .
Besides , in this weather ... Only ghosts would stick around .
That 's right , we came here especially to catch a ghost .
Disperse and look around .
Brother wai , there 's a cave here .
Huh ? Really ?
Hey ...
You two , go inside and take a look .
Us ? If there 's a vampire , we 'll be so screwed !
What 're you afraid of ? I 'm right behind youl !
Uncle gau , what kind of ghost did he meet ?
I think he met a female ghost .
Will he be alright ?
He 'll be alright .
Much better off than man choi .
Wow ! So many love bites . She must 've been one horny ghost .
It 's dark already .
How long have I been sleeping ?
All day .
Damn ! I haven 't been back to the store all day .
Auntie 's going to kill me for sure !
You still remember your aunt ?
Master , what else can I do to help ?
If you don 't give me anymore trouble , I 'll chuckle to myself in secret .
Hey ! Are you alright ?
I 'm fine ...
Master , I 'm going now .
Fine . Go back early , then !
Ting-ting , watch man choi for me .
I 'm going out a while , be back soon .
Siu yuk !
Don 't come near !
What 's painted on your body ?
Master must have painted it .
He 's always afraid I 'll meet a ghost .
I don 't like it . Wipe it off .
Don 't wipe it off , stupid boy !
Siu yuk ...
Let me see what you really look like .
Let me soothe it for you .
Brother sang , save me !
Bullying my girlfriend ?
Brother sang !
Don 't worry , I 'll untie it for you .
Hey , are you crazy ? Don 't recklessly untie it !
Trying to bribe me with money ?
It 's not that easy !
Stupid boy ...
What the hell happened ?
Was I dreaming ?
Dreaming ?
You were enchanted by a ghost , stupid boy !
Good lord , I 'd already thought of that .
Lucky you found out late .
Late ? If I hadn 't rescued you in time ,
you 'd be dead from sexual exhaustion . Talk about late !
Master , it 's because you found out late ,
I could get lucky with her .
Had you found out earlier she was a ghost ,
I wouldn 't have had a dreamy romantic night .
Stupid boy ! You have sex on the brain !
Look at the two of youl !
One 's poisoned by a corpse , and the other 's obsessed with a ghost .
It 's my bad luck to have apprentices like you .
Master , my poison 's expulsion is almost complete .
My bewitchment is almost complete .
Look at you !
Babbling without rhyme or reason .
Your bewitchment really is almost complete .
So , what now ?
Alright .
When that ghost comes tonight ,
I 'll exorcise it !
Uncle gau , drink tea .
Thanks .
Better take refuge in your room .
Stay there , no matter what you hear .
Hey , you sleeping ?
Why can 't I sleep ?
It 's you who 's possessed , not me .
So , you 're ignoring me ?
If I was ignoring you , I 'd be asleep in my room .
What more do you want from me ?
What 's wrong ? Have you got cold shivers ?
No ...
Brother sang ...
Brother sang !
Hey , untie me .
Hey !
Brother sang , save me !
Hey ! What are you doing ?
Hey ! Man choi , no !
Man choi , no !
Master , help me ...
I am helping youl !
Master ! Hurry and let me out , or I 'm dead !
You be quiet !
Calm down , be patient , and everything will be fine .
Never fear , master 's here !
Look out ! Behind youl !
- Get back ! - Brother sang !
Brother sang ...
Don 't look at her .
Let 's go !
Stay there !
Siu yuk !
Master , don 't !
After all , she saved me once .
If master exorcises her , she 'll never be reincarnated .
Don 't you realise that humans and ghosts can 't be together ?
Keep pestering him like this , you 'll only end up killing him .
Master , let her go .
If I let her go , then she won 't let you go !
Take care of her yourself .
There 's another one !
After eating all that glutinous rice , how come he 's still like this ?
Good lord !
No wonder .
Glutinous rice mixed with long-grain rice .
How can he recover ?
" How to cure vampires "
Be patient .
Almost there , nearly done .
Done !
How do you feel ?
I 'm fine . I 've fully recovered .
- Really ? - Yes .
Good ! If you feel pain , you 're fine .
Uncle Gaul !
Uncle gau , that vampire 's in the village again .
Oh ? Wait a moment .
Seal all the doors and windows .
Sprinkle glutinous rice on the floor .
Remember , you mustn 't leave this house , not even half a step .
Get up and help , then !
That vampire did it again .
What should we do , uncle gau ?
Take him back to the yamen first .
Whoa , no way !
After last time , I 'm already scared !
If you have no objection , burn him on a lychee wood pyre .
Fine . Men , carry him out and burn him !
Yes !
Uncle gau , it 's ready !
Light the fire .
Hey .
Open the door ...
Why did you close the door ?
Huh ? I was looking to see if the door was strong enough .
What are you afraid of ?
I 'd be lying if I wasn 't afraid !
Hey , don 't be such a coward .
See ? We 're all sealed up .
A fly couldn 't even get in , never mind a vampire !
Master 's back .
Hey , open the door , then .
Quick , come back inside !
Close the door ...
Give it to me .
Go . I have to go .
Hey , are you crazy ?
What happens if master can 't get in ?
Open the door ...
- Master 's back ! - Master 's back !
- Master , he 's here ... - I know .
Bring the work tools out .
Close the door . Look after ting-ting .
Close the door !
Come on , block the door .
Hey , is it safe in here ?
Hey , can 't you see it 's all sealed up ?
Whoa ! No wonder it 's so hot . I can 't even breathe .
Don 't fret , there 's a skylight .
- Oh , that 's better . - Skylight ?
Huh ? Oh , shit !
Come on , I 'll lift you up .
Get up ...
Strange , I definitely remember the skylight being closed .
How can it be open ?
You can 't be serious ?
Don 't scare me !
Look closer .
Man choi !
Man choi , are you alright ?
- Open the door ! - Open the door !
What are you doing ?
This way .
Big brother , eat the chicken ...
Delicious .
Uncle gau , help me ...
Master !
Master , he can see .
Attack his eyes !
You go !
Go now !
Man choi , let 's go !
It 's alright ! What 's going on ?
Vampire !
The real deal !
Gang of brothers , lend a helping hand .
Forward !
Rise up !
Help suck out the vampire 's breath with your mouth !
Quickly !
Suck !
Let me .
Oh , shit !
My clients !
Oh , no ...
Starring : Ricky hui , moon Lee , chin siu-ho , lam ching-ying , pauline wong , Billy la ...
Guest stars : Anthony chan , wu ma . Co-starring : Wong ha , yuen wah .
Mr vampire